(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E07 -= Weekend.Fantasy =- Subripped by zerox
杰森，晚餐不知怎么办了
Jason, I don't know what we're gonna do about dinner.
要完成报导，我要加班
I've got to work late tonight or I'll never finish that story.
麦克3点钟要看牙医
Don't forget Mike's got that dentist appointment at 3:00.
我可以取消3点钟的病人
I can take him. I cancelled my 3:00 patient...
把幽闭恐惧症推迟到6点
I moved my claustrophobic back to 6:00.
那病人懂做饭吗？
Great. Can he cook?
也许吧，只要不在电梯里就行
Maybe. As long as he's not in an elevator.
算了，我带外卖回来吧
Never mind. I'll pick up something.
我们很久没单独相处了
You know how long it's been since you and I have been alone together?
我们现在就单独相处了
We're alone now.
我是说没有孩子打扰.
I'm talking about alone. I mean, without our children...
没有工作妨碍，没有衣服间隔
without our work, without our clothes.
妈妈，我的翅膀呢？
Mom, where are my wings?
控制中心，看来我要在厨房降落了
Houston, it looks like I'm going to have to bring her down in the kitchen.
妈妈，麦克! 我10分钟后就要排练了!
Mom. Come on, Mike! I've got a dress rehearsal in 10 minutes!
发现敌机，殊死搏斗
Oh, no, enemy plane. Looks like a definite dogfight.
-麦克! -妈妈!
- Mike! - Mom!
麦克，别再扫射你妹妹
Okay, Mike, will you stop shooting your sister...
把翅膀还给那小朋友
and give the kid back his wings?
好的
Okay.
西弗在中场截到球.
And Seaver steals the ball at mid-court.
左边假动作，右边假动作，上前得分!
He fakes left, fakes right, goes up and scores!
犯规
Foul.
够了，谁最后一个上校车.
That's it. Now the last one on that school bus...
谁就要吃一个星期爸爸的煎饼
has to eat your fathers pancakes for a week.
真恶心!
Gross!
-再见 -再见
- Bye. - Later, guys.
说得好!
Nice.
对不起，我怎么才能补偿你？
I'm sorry, honey. How can I make it up to you, huh?
这个也许能指引你
Well, see if this gives you any ideas.
“布朗克斯受贿”？
"Bronx gorilla takes bride"?
不，这里
No, read that.
“雪山周末度假，189.95元”
"Mount Snow getaway weekend. $189.95."
杰森，瞧
Jason, look.
住在哈特里酒店 记得上次我们下榻那里吗？
It's at the Hartley Inn. Remember the last time we we were there?
记得，15年前
Yes. Fifteen years ago.
度蜜月
Right after we we're married.
记得我们还没有使用吊车卷呢
As I recall, we never did use our lift tickets.
9个月后麦克就出生了
And nine months later we had Mike.
也许当年我们应该去滑雪
Maybe we should have done a little skiing.
找个时间去滑雪也不错
Boy, wouldn't it be fun to do that sometime?
-这个周末怎样？ -什么？
- Well, how about this weekend? - What?
对，麦姬，我们就去一把
Yeah, come on, Maggie. Why don't we just go for it?
-真的？ -真的
- Really? - Really.
那就好玩了
Boy, it would be so much fun.
算算，189.95乘以2
Lets see, $189.95 times two.
本能不能买半票呢？
Do you think they'd charge full price for Ben?
不!我是说属于我们的周末
No! Because I'm talking about a Ben-less weekend.
没有本，没有凯罗，没有麦克
A Ben-less, Carol-less, Mike-less weekend.
你也太挑剔了吧？
That's a pretty exclusive guest list.
我就是个势利鬼
Yeah, well, call me a snob.
我们哪有时间请保姆？
Jason, where are we going to find a sitter on such short notice?
-我有个合适人选 -谁？
- I have the perfect candidate. - Who?
-坐下 -麦克不行
- Sit down. - Not Mike.
求你坐下好吗
I beg you to sit down.
我们从没让他看家超过6小时
But, Jason, we've never left him in charge for more than six hours.
最大的原因是家里有我
Yeah, well, our homeowners policy covered most of that.
拜托，有什么问题？
Come on, what's the problem?
他15岁了，却连驾照也没有
Honey, he's 15. He doesn't even have his drivers license.
房子不用开走，房子住就好了
He doesn't have to drive the house, he only has to sit in it.
我知道，但这算是个突破
I know, but it's just that it's such a big step.
我承认是个突破，我们的突破
I agree. It's a very big step. For us.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
承认孩子长大了也是困难的事
I mean, it's tough to admit sometimes that your kids are growing up.
那小子刚把水果投进弟弟头上的光环
Jason, the boy just slam-dunked a grapefruit through his brothers halo.
麦克能处理这种情况的
I think Mike should be able to handle something like this.
问题是我们能否处理
The question is, can we handle it?
你真的认为可以？
You really think they'd be okay?
我真的认为可以
I really think they'd be okay.
好吧，若他们能处理 我也能处理
Okay, if they can handle it, I can handle it.
-那就是去了？ -是的
- Then you'll go? - You bet.
那就尽情放松好了
And you'll kick back and relax.
杰森，在你面前的是.
Jason, you are looking...
轻松女王
at the first lady of relaxation.
好，再说一次紧急电话号码
Okay, one more time. Emergency phone numbers.
贴在厨房的冰箱上
In the kitchen, on the refrigerator.
好，中毒急救，强酸，强碱，汽油产品
Okay, poison drill. Strong alkalis, acids, petroleum products.
叫救护车，喝牛奶
Call the paramedics and drink milk.
还有呢？
Everything else?
去看医生，呕吐
Check with the doctor and throw up.
原来是轻松女王
If it isn't the first lady of relaxation.
只是确保一下，别小题大做
We're just going over a few things, Jason. Let's not make a big deal out of it.
麦克，给你100块
Mike, heres $100.
不用干活就有100块，谢谢
I was going to do this for nothing, but thanks.
紧急情况下才能用
That's for emergency use only.
紧急约会可以吗？
So, like, if we have emergency dates?
说笑啦
Just kidding, Dad.
幽默可以舒缓情绪
I find that humor keeps the little ones at ease.
麦克，谢谢你的提点
Thanks for the tip, Mike.
你们要好好相处
Now, we want you guys to all try and get along.
麦克现在做主
Mike is in charge.
我保证若出了什么差错.
And I want to reassure you that if anything should go amiss...
必定严明执法
justice will be swift and severe.
爸爸，想出一个权力平衡的机制.
Dad, don't you think there should be like a system...
这样好不好？
of checks and balances here?
我同意让麦克掌权.
I mean, I can accept that Mike has a certain authority...
-但我和本需要.. -球棍
- just so Ben and I have-- - Baseball bats.
我去开门
I'll get that.
下午好，我是百科全书公司的人
Good afternoon. I'm from the Facts Are Us encyclopedia company.
对不起，我的家长现在没空
I'm sorry, sir. But my parents really don't have time at the moment.
他们这个周末要外出
You see, they're about to go away for the weekend.
谢谢，旅途愉快
Okay, thank you anyway. Have a nice trip.
麦克，你永远也不应该.
Mike, you should never ever tell someone like that...
告诉这种人父母不在家
that your parents aren't going to be home.
出师不利
Not off to a great start, Mike.
没事，这家伙看上去不像什么连环杀手
Okay. I mean, this guy did not look like the psycho killer type.
这样啊，聪明人，连环杀手是怎样的？
I see. Tell me, smart guy, what exactly does the psycho killer type look like?
很好
That's very good.
够了，够了
Okay, that's it. That's everything.
我们要很晚才能到达酒店
Look, by the time we get to the hotel it might be very late.
-你们今晚要干什么？ -在家玩吧
- What are you guys going to do tonight? - Probably just hang out.
-那么早上打电话给你们 -好
- Okay, so well call you in the morning. - Right.
我们走了
We're out of here.
我和爸爸就靠你了，我们深信.
Your father and I are relying on you, Mike, and we have the utmost confidence...
你能看管好这房子.
in your ability to take care of the house and...
看管好我的孩子
my babies.
滑雪时间到了
Snow time.
我们这次是信任你才去的
Now, we wouldn't be doing this if we didn't trust you, Mike.
麦姬，走吧
Maggie, lets go.
好的
Okay.
再见
Bye, everybody.
我做得到
I think I can.
楼梯好像加长了
They've added stairs, you know.
-杰森，瞧 -真漂亮
- Jason, look at this. - Looks great.
跟15年前一模一样
It's the same room we had 15 years ago.
同样的家具，同样的景色
Same furniture, same view.
同样的肥皂，都是一样的
Same bar of soap. Not everything's the same.
不过为了保护我们，厕所清理过
No, they've sanitized the toilet for our protection.
酒店当然希望物品耐用
I'm sure they held off as long as they could.
记得我们第一晚做些什么吗？
Remember what we did here, that very first night?
你发疯了
You we're crazy.
-疯够了吗？ -不知道
- You still that crazy? - Oh, I don't know.
-我挑战你 -加倍
- Come on, I dare you. - Double dare?
成交
You're on.
当年的疯狂还是不减
Still crazy after all these years.
小心
Look out.
我们该打电话回家
You know, maybe we should call the kids.
谁说我们要打回家？
Did somebody say we should call the kids?
-他们似乎很遥远 -是的
- I mean, they feel so far away. - Yeah.
-300英里远 -是的
- You know, 300 miles away. - Yeah.
想想看300里外的人会变得多小？
Can you imagine how tiny they'd look from 300 miles away?
是啊
Yeah.
无依无靠，孤苦伶仃
How lost, how helpless, how abandoned.
麦姬，已经10点过后了
Maggie, it's after 10:00.
明早再打回家吧
We said we'd call them in the morning.
-我明白 -而且本睡了
- I know, but-- - And Bens asleep.
你也不想吵醒他吧？
You really don't want to wake him up now, do you?
宝贝，你去解开行李吧
Sweetheart, why don't you just start unpacking or something?
好的
Okay. All right.
首先要叠好你的毛衣
I'll start by putting away your sweater.
亲爱的，怎么了？
Come on, honey, what's the matter?
响了7次，没人接
Jason, the phone's rung seven times, and there's no answer.
8，9.
Eight, nine...
ten.
杰森，响27次了
Jason, that's 27 rings.
-也许熟睡了 -29次
- Maybe they're sound asleep. - Twenty-nine rings.
3个人不会都听不到，30次了
Three people could not sleep through 30 rings.
每次只会响10次
That's only 10 rings apiece.
等等，让我试试
Wait a minute, honey, come on. Let me try. Okay?
也许我打错号码了
Maybe you dialed a wrong number.
打错，对，有可能
A wrong number. You're right. I could have done that.
虽然没试过，但有可能
I don't think I did that, but I could have done that.
怎样？
Well?
没人接，暂时而已 才响了4次
No answer, yet. Honey, it's only been four rings.
加上我的30次，出问题了
Plus my 30. Jason, something's wrong.
会是什么问题？
What could it be?
烧烤汉堡包
Grilled hamburgers, all right.
爸妈会同意我们烧烤吗？
Mike, do you really think Mom and Dad would let us have a barbecue?
大惊小怪，我们也不是没试过
What's the big wow, Carol? We've had a barbecue before.
没有在客厅烧烤过
Never in the living room.
她说得有道理
She's got a point there.
好吧，到厨房烧烤
Yeah, all right, I'll do it in the kitchen.
这东西怎么弄？
How's this thing work, anyway?
算了，我来
Never mind, I got it.
凯罗，再一个杯子
Carol, hand me another glass.
谢谢
Thanks.
麦克，拜托!我不要全熟的!
Come on, Mike, I wanted mine rare!
快!我要救火
Quick, I need something to cover the fire!
混帐!要重来了
Unbelievable! Now I have to start all over again.
太迟了，控制不了
It's too late! It's out of control!
今晚看来要出去吃了
Guess this means we're eating out tonight.
麦姬，你的想象力太丰富了
Maggie, I think your imagination has gotten the better of you.
麦克是不会在屋里烧烤的
Mike would not barbecue our house.
发生什么事了？怎么不接电话
Then what's going on? Why won't they answer the phone?
我们冷静想想看
Why don't we just think about this calmly for a minute, okay?
他们不会做傻事
We know they wouldn't do anything crazy.
也许是他们一起去玩了
Maybe they just decided to do something together.
好玩的事情
Something they could all enjoy.
“第一章，我爸爸姓菲里”
"Chapter 1. My fathers family name being Pirrip...
“我受洗的名字是菲利普，小时候..”
"and my Christian name, Philip, my infant tongue could make of both names...
“我只能把这两个都念成菲”
"nothing longer or more explicit than Pip."
我去开门
I'll get it.
被你抢先一步了!
Darn, I was just getting into it!
记得妈妈的话，别让陌生人进来
Remember what Mom said, "Don't open the door to strangers."
他不是陌生人，我们见过他
He's no stranger. He's somebody we know.
-晚上好 -你好，进来吧
- Good evening. - Hi, how are you doing? Come on in.
谢谢，只有你们在？
Thank you. Thank you very much. You kiddies all alone?
没关系，我能做主
No problem, sir. Any decision that needs to be made, I can handle it.
这样的话，我有东西让你们看
In that case, I have something very special I'd like to show you.
好了!举起手!
All right! Hands up!
过去沙发那边!
Okay, over by the couch!
难以置信!
Unbelievable!
用机关枪就想让我们买你的.
If you think that machine guns gonna make us buy one of your...
-狗屁百科全书？ -闭嘴
- stupid encyclopedias-- - Shut up!
拿着
And hold this.
其实，这只是把冲锋枪
Actually, this is a submachine gun.
有谁知道发明这种武器的美国人是谁？
Can anyone here tell me who first developed this weapon in America?
汤普森，这是一把汤普森冲锋枪
Thompson. This is a Thompson submachine gun.
若是有百科全书，你们肯定会知道
Something you might know if you owned a set of my encyclopedias.
可是你们的父母就是不买
No, your parents couldn't be bothered.
他们都忙于取笑我，你们都在取笑我
They we're too busy laughing at me. You we're all laughing at me.
-全世界都在取笑我 -去当喜剧演员就好了
- The whole world laughs at me. - Maybe you could become a comedian.
你去当一块猪肉好了!
And maybe you, little boy, could become a pork chop!
-不接电话？ -好主意
- Aren't you going to get the phone? - Good idea.
谢谢你的一席话，我现在好多了
Thanks for sharing that with me, Jason. I feel much better now.
打给谁？
Who are you calling?
-打给库斯曼 -好
- I'm calling Ellen Coozman. - Good.
喂，艾伦？我是杰森.西弗
Hello, Ellen? Yes, this is Jason Seaver.
是的，我们打回家没人接
Yeah, well, we just called the kids, and there was no answer...
你们可以到隔壁.
so we just wondered maybe if you could run next door...
看一看怎么回事吗？
and take a look at them and....
好的，谢谢
Would you? Okay. Good, thank you.
他们回头打过来
She's going to call us right back from the house.
我就知道这是错误的
Jason, I knew this was a mistake.
我们不应该丢下他们
We should have never ever left them alone.
亲爱的，别慌张
Honey, lets not panic, okay?
总会有合理的解释.
I still say there's gonna be some reasonable explanation...
为什么不接电话
why they're not answering the phone.
例如呢？
Yeah? Like?
例如孩子们常常会害怕接电话
Well, like, it's not unusual for kids to become phone-shy.
艾伦？对
Ellen? Yes.
什么？不在家？
What? They're not there.
天哪，他们去哪里了？
God, where on earth could they be?
不知道
I don't know.
麦克，气色不错!
Yo, Michael, looking good!
你们有身份证吗？
Hey, you kids got IDs?
有，看吧
Yeah, here you go, my man.
凯罗.西弗，生于1953年，很好
Carol Seaver, born 1953. Looks good to me.
本.西弗，退伍军人，越战兵？
Ben Seaver, army discharge. Nam, huh?
-是的 -战争如何？
- Yep. - How was it?
惨不忍睹
It was hell.
这地方太棒了
Wow, Mike. This place is awesome!
怎么以前不带我们来？
Yeah, how come you didn't bring us here before?
你们也知道爸妈多么的保守
Well, you know how old-fashioned Mom and Dad are.
没关系了 我明天就逃学来这里工作
It won't matter after tonight because l"m dumping school and starting work here.
-行不行？ -行
- Right, Slash? - All right, Seaver.
保镖越多越好
I can always use another bouncer.
你俩呢？找工作？
What about you two? Looking for work?
是的，我要做酒保
Yeah, I want to be a bartender!
-我可以做服务员 -可以，宝贝
- I could be a waitress. - You got it, toots.
麦克，你身上有些东西不在我身上
Hey, Mike, parts of me have been missing parts of you.
-把我整个拿去吧 -好吧
- Why not take all of me? - All right.
老兄，帮帮忙
Hey, buddy, do me a favor.
-保管一下 -好的
- Keep this for me. - Sure.
-三杯烈酒，一杯调酒 -马上就好
- Three shooters and a bull maker. - Coming up.
宝贝，你去哪里了？
Hey, babe, where you been all my life, huh?
上学了，放开我!
In school. Now, leave me alone!
来吻一个，轻轻吻一个，过来
Come here, give me a kiss. Just a little kiss. Come here.
小子你给我看好
Hey, watch it, dude!
你有话要说吗？
You got something to say, tough guy?
动手啊，正合我意
Go ahead, make my day.
我要报警
I'm calling the Huntington police.
516-555-9622
516-555-9622.
我是个记者兼母亲 这些号码我知道
I'm a mother, I'm a reporter. I know these things.
喂，警察局？ 对，我是杰森.西弗
Hello, have I reached the police? Yes, this is Jason Seaver.
对，麦克的爸爸
Yes, Mikes dad.
有3名失踪儿童
I want to report three missing children...
失踪至少5分钟了
and it's been at least five minutes.
有可能是7分钟
No, it could be seven, it might be seven minutes.
我和内子在佛蒙特州 把孩子留在家
My wife and I are in Vermont, and we left the kids alone.
对，让麦克当保姆
Yes, with Mike.
我们打给邻居，邻居过去看 孩子不在家
We phoned the neighbors, and they went to check the house, the kids aren't there.
罗宾路15号
15, Robin Lane.
谢谢
Thank you. Yes. Okay.
杰森，你没留下这里的号码
Jason, you didn't leave them our phone number here.
对，因为我们要回家了
No, that's because we're going home.
开车要5小时
But, honey, it's a five-hour drive.
我们可以坐飞机，再转出租车
We can fly down and well take a cab, okay?
-我们不会在这里 -好的
- That's where we belong. - Okay. Okay.
护目镜拿了没有？
Did you get, you got the goggles, didn't you?
-拿了，谢谢 -好吧
- Please, yes, thanks. - Okay. All right.
见鬼，钥匙折了
I have it, the damn keys bent now.
-没插错钥匙吧？ -这是什么？
- You sure you have the right one? - Well, what does that look like?
酒店房间的钥匙
The hotel key.
麦克，怎么了？我很困
Mike, what's going on? I'm tired.
瞧，有人进入家里了
Look, there's somebody in the house.
你们跳到车房顶，爬树下来
I want you guys to go down the garage roof, climb out on the oak tree...
接着到库斯曼家报警，去
and call the police from the Coozmans. Go on.
杰森，他们真的不在家，怎么办？
Oh, no, Jason. They're really not here. What are we gonna do?
打电话到警察局，快
Well check back with the police. Okay, come on.
对，对，谢谢
Yes, yes, please. Thank you very much.
警察11点来过，孩子们都在家
Well, the police we're here at 11 :00, and all the kids we're here then.
但现在都不在
But, Jason, they're gone now.
我知道，警察局会派人来
I know. They're gonna send another patrol car over right away.
别动!
Freeze!
-真快 -举起手，到一边去
- That was quick. - Hands up. Over by the rail.
-不，这个.. -快!
- No, you see-- - Move it!
好吧
All right.
-我们是西弗家的，我们住在这里 -西弗家的人去佛蒙特州了
- But we're the Seavers. We live here. - The Seavers are in Vermont, lady.
不，我们飞回来了，我们就是他们
No, we flew back. We're them. We're home.
好，身份证
All right, lets see some ID, pal.
照片照得不好
It's not a good picture.
好吧，你出去把孩子们带进屋
All right, why don't you go outside and get those kids and bring them in here?
-他们在哪里？安全吗？ -找到孩子们了？
- Where are they? Are they safe? - You've found the kids.
他们好好的
Well, they we're fine...
后来他们听到鬼鬼祟祟的声音 他们报警了
until they heard some prowlers downstairs and called the cops.
不可能是我父母，他们在佛蒙特州
They can't be my parents. My parents are in Vermont.
真是不敢相信
I don't believe this.
-孩子们 -且慢
- My babies. - Not so fast.
麦克，这是你父母？
Mike, are these your parents?
或者是易容高手
Either that, or somebody's very clever with make-up.
你们去哪里了？真担心你们
Where we're you? We worried about you.
谢谢你的玩笑
Hey, thanks for keeping things fun.
你们回来干什么？
What are you guys doing here?
晚上叫警察来还不够？
I mean, wasn't it enough to send the cops by once this evening?
我们打电话回家，你们不在
But, Mike, we called and you weren't here.
你们说明早才会打来
You said you weren't going to call till tomorrow.
这个不重要，你们去哪里了？
That's not the point, Mike. Where the hell we're you?
莫西太太做了蛋糕，请我们过去吃
Mrs. Moisiodi's made a bundt cake. She invited us over for dessert.
接着她放旅游幻灯片
And then she pulled out the vacation slides.
她们去过许多地方
They went everywhere.
我们10点打来时，你们去哪了？
But we called at 10:00, Mike. Where we're you then?
挪威
Norway.
妈妈，你得记住.
Something to bear in mind, Mom.
全世界的海峡都是一个样的
If you've seen one fjord, you've seen them all.
真的吗？
Is that all true, Carol?
其实是点心，不算蛋糕
Well, actually it was more a strudel than a bundt cake.
其余的都是真的
And the rest of it is about right.
你们以为我们干什么了？
What did you guys think we we're doing here, anyway?
我们发过誓不会把父母的 某些做法.
Remember how we always swore we'd never do certain things to our kids...
应用在我们的孩子身上
that our parents did to us?
我们刚刚却用了其中一项
Did we just do one of those things to our kids?
难说，我们还算处理得当
I don't know. I think we handled it pretty well under the circumstances.
-情况还不算太坏 -还能怎么坏？
- it could have been a lot worse. - How?
有可能是我俩去看莫西太太的幻灯片
It could have been us watching Mrs. Moisiodi's vacation slides.
杰森
Jason.
看来我们成为普通的父母了
I guess we turned out to be pretty normal parents after all.
麦姬，我们很普通吗？
Oh, no, Maggie. Are we normal?
-真可怕 -是啊
- Pretty scary, isn't it? - it is.
普通的父母.
Say, do you think two normal parents...
会不会在凌晨3点.
would go out at 3:00 in the morning...
出去吃香蕉圣代冰淇淋？
for a double-dipped banana fudge sundae surprise?
不大可能
I doubt it.
-想做不普通的父母吗？ -乐意至极
- You want to be abnormal? - Love to.
好，你去告诉麦克我们要出去
Okay, you go tell Mike we're going out...
-我去把车启动 -杰森，还有一个问题
- and I'll warm up the Volvo. - Jason, there's just one problem.
-什么？ -车子在佛蒙特州
- What? - The Volvos in Vermont.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.12